A Guide to the Mark Kac papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA170
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Laboratory Notebooks, 1942-1964; 5; 4.84 Cubic Feet
  - 1953 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Summer 1953 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - 1954 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - 1957 November (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - 1959 March (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - 1960s (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - 1960 January (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - 1960 July-August (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - 1961 January-June (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - 1961 March (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - 1961 September (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - 1962 January (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - 1962 October (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - 1963 January (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - 1963 February (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - 1963 April-May (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - 1963 June (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - 1963 July (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - 1963 August (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - 1964 January (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - 1964 May, Book 1 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - 1964 May, Book 2 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - 1965 January, Book 3 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - 1965 July (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - 1966 June (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - 1966 August (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - 1967 February, Book 6 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - 1967 October (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - 1968 December-1969 June (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - 1968 December (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - 1969 August (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - 1970 October (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - 1971 March (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - 1971 August (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - 197? February (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - 1973 November (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - 1974 August (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Algebra Over the Complex Number (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Analytic Number Theory (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Benel Functions (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Complex Variables (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Complex Variables-Math 531/32, 1 of 2 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Complex Variables-Math 531/32, 2 of 2 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Derivation of Boltzmann's Equation (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Ehrenfest Example (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Ehrenfest Model (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Equation of Continuity (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - 4-body Toda Problem (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Generalized Diffusion Theory (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Kinetic Theory, 1 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Kinetic Theory, 2 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Kinetic Theory and Related Topics (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Langenian Equation for a Brownian Particle (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Linear Boltzmann Equation (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Linville's Equation (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Marnoff Chains (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - "Master Equation" for the Simplified Model (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Mathematical Physics (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Mathematics 400 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Mathematics 721-22 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Matrix of Transitions Probabilities (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Method of Steepest Descent (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1 of 2 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 of 2 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous II (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Moran Models (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Non-linear Models (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, 1946 August 1 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, 1946 August 2 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, 1947 March 5 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, 1946 November 9 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - "On the Distribution of Distances of Points Chosen at Random" (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - "On the Distribution of Eigenvalues of Certain Integral Equations" (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - "On the Theory of Random Noise in Radio Receivers" (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Particle Density (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Princeton, 1951-1952 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - "Probabilistic Approach to Kinetic Theory of Gases" (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Propagation of sound in rarefied gases (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Ray's derivation of Spitzer's Theorem (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Rayleigh's treatment of convection (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Remarks on the first passage time for the Uhlenbeck-Ornstein Process (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Remarks on Markoff Chains (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Rotating bucket notes (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Second Law of Thermodynamics (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Spherical Model (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Statistical Mechanics Seminar Spring, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Statistical Thermodynamics (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Stellar Statistics (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Three-body Toda problem (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Theory of Random Process, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Translation Kernels (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Two-dimensional Markoff Process (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Uhlenbeck's Notebook on Quantum Electrodynamics (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - [unidentified] (Box 55, Folder 9)
- Audio-Visual Material, 1960s; 6; 0.5 Cubic Feet
  Recordings of several lectures and 14 glass slides, unidentified.
  Arranged in chronological order by title of lecture.
  - "Role of Mathematical Models in Science", 1969 February 12 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
  - "How to Hear the Shape of a Drum", 1964 August; Takes 1-9 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - "How to Hear the Shape of a Drum", 1964 August; Takes 10-16 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - "How to Hear the Shape of a Drum", 1964 August; Takes 17-22 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - "Computer Music" (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - "Wiener" (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - [unidentified reel] (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - 14 unidentified glass slides, 1964 (Box 56)
- Student Thesis, 1940-1982; 7; 1.32 Cubic Feet
  Includes students' theses who had been advised by Kac.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by student's last name.
  - Eustaquio S. Baclig, Jr., 1953 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Harlan G.H. Bartram, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Donald Elro Bedo, 1957 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Jack Logan Bellamy, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Martin Roy Bates, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Tseng Tung Cheng, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Robert Cohen, 1956 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Joanne Elliott, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Ernest Slavko Elyash, 1950 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Charles Hatfield Jr., 1944 (Box 58)
  - James Henry Hayes (Box 58)
  - Phillip S. Jastram (Box 58)
  - Mario Leon Juncosa, 1945 (Box 58)
  - Talbot Michael Katz, 1982 (Box 58)
  - Harry Kesten, 1958 (Box 58)
  - Abraham Morton Mark, 1945 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Abraham Morton Mark, 1947 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Henry S. McGaughan, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - David Frederick Neu, 1960 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - David S. Newman, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Alfred Milton Peiser, 1944 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Murray Rosenblatt, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Irma Schocken, 1946 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Jerome C. Smith, 1945 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Murray R. Spiegel, 1949 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Alan Gustave Konheim, 1960 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Paul Joseph Lochak, 1951 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - William Judson Leveque, 1947 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Charles C. Torrance, 1927 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Michael Waldner, 1948 (Box 60, Folder 6)
- Personal File, 1939-1984; 8; 0.25 Cubic Feet
  Includes biographical material and photographs.
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - Biographical material (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 61, Folder 2)